# **Colin Hughes**

1401 Gaylord St Apt 8, Denver, CO 80206 colin.s.hughes@gmail.com ● (440) 799-5238 http://www.bgdprods.com

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

Seeking a senior level, or similar development position using whatever technologies get the job done. Challenging and engaging work is strongly preferred.

#### **STRENGTHS AND SKILLS**

All of my professional experience has been as *full stack* developer, which means that I was responsible for creating solutions from the data through to the user interface. I also offer excellent communication and writing skills, especially when it comes to technical subjects. Here is a list of the technologies with which I am an expert:

- Object-oriented C#, Java, C/C++ STL
- Scripting JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, ECMAScript 2015 (ES2015), JQuery
- Database Microsoft SQL Server, MongoDB, MySQL
- Frontend Application Frameworks Angular, ASP.NET MVC 4/5, ASP.NET, ASP Classic, Castle Monorail
- Miscellaneous
  - HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, XML, JSON
  - .NET, MEAN, LAMP
  - o Razor, nVelocity, EJS, JADE
  - o Entity Framework, nHibernate
  - Telerik, ArcGIS, Bootstrap, ReactiveX, lodash
  - o RESTful web services, WCF, AJAX, XHR
  - Windows Forms, Android, Java Foundation Classes
  - o Git, Team Foundation Services, Subversion, TortoiseSVN, SourceGear Vault, GitHub
  - o IIS, Azure, Apache, Nginx
  - Windows, Linux, Bash, PowerShell
  - Visual Studio, Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, SQL Sever Management Studio

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### .NET/WEB DEVELOPER

Ramboll Environ, Denver, CO – October 2015 – Present

 Delivered multiple projects that I developed from conception to final release; talked with clients about the scope and purpose of a project, wrote time and cost estimates based on the guidelines, and then worked with a small team or individually to create the final release within the given budget.

- Developed a tool that would let entities collect their greenhouse gas inventories into a central
  database using many different methods (forms, bulk uploads from various file formats, etc.). The
  user could then use the interface to aggregate and display the data dynamically using criteria of
  their choosing.
- Created websites integrated with ArcGIS maps that would allow the users to alter the map layer information, and subsequently see the changes in real time.
- Core applications development was done using ASP.NET MVC 4/5, and ASP.NET.

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Adeptive Software, Louisville, CO – May 2014 – July 2015

- Developed a multitude of enhancements, plugins, and bug fixes for *ResWare* (Adeptive Software's core application), which is an all-encompassing real estate industry software solution.
- Consistently delivered pieces of larger projects in an agile environment on time and within estimations.
- Personally developed multiple bank wire integration plugins. Typically the wire transfers used proprietary file formats, encryption, and SFTP.
- Core applications development was done in WinForms, and ASP.NET, with primary web service development being done using WCF, and RESTful.

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER/HELP DESK SPECIALIST

Dimension Technology Solutions, Littleton, CO – Feb 2014 – April 2014

- Developed the procedures and tools that allowed *eMESA* to seamlessly integrate with existing ERP systems such as Ellipse, Oracle, and SunSystems.
- Day to day maintenance of around a dozen websites that used Dimension Technology Solution's core web application eMESA.
- Routinely fixed bugs for legacy versions of eMESA that had been outstanding for years.
- Communicated directly with clients to resolve any issues.
- Core development was done using a proprietary setup of Castle Monorail (C#, nVelocity, nHibernate, MS SQL).

### JUNIOR SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Dimension Technology Solutions, Littleton, CO - Oct 2013 - Feb 2014

• All of the same responsibilities listed above with a lesser role in day to day communication with clients.

#### **EDUCATION**

**Cleveland State University**, Monte Ahuja College of Business Bachelors of Science in Computer Information Science